const e="commerce",t=200,a=49,i=[{id:295,question:"The wealth of a nation depend on the volume of its",option:{a:"bilateral trade activities",b:"commercial activities",c:"multilateral trade activities",d:"stock market"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:296,question:"Which of the following can be used to differentiate skilled and unskilled lab our? ",option:{a:"education and training",b:"available resources ",c:"level of commitment",d:"salaries and wages"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:297,question:"A doctor who attends to patients at home after his official duty is",option:{a:"A community development worker",b:"a direct service worker",c:"an indirect service worker ",d:"a direct and an indirect worker"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:298,question:"Manufacturing and construction activities are class8ified under",option:{a:"Primary production",b:"Tertiary production",c:"secondary production",d:"direct production"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:299,question:"The reward of rent, wages, interest and profits accrue from",option:{a:"capitals, labour, land, and entrepreneur respectively",b:"land entrepreneur, labour and capital respectively",c:"land, labour, capital, and entrepreneur respectively",d:"labour, entrepreneur, land and capital respectively."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:300,question:"The factor of production that is subject to depreciation is",option:{a:"capital ",b:"land",c:"labour",d:"entrepreneur"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:301,question:"Division of labour ultimately leads to ",option:{a:"conservation",b:"integration",c:"specialization",d:"repetition"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:302,question:"A worker who process rice is engaged in",option:{a:"constructive activity",b:"commercial activity",c:"extractive activity",d:"Manufacturing activity"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:303,question:"After- sales service is a function usually rendered by",option:{a:"a retailer",b:"a wholesaler ",c:"an agent ",d:"an entrepreneur "},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:304,question:"A trend is retailing which enables consumers to have free access to different products is ",option:{a:"after sales service ",b:"branding ",c:"self-service",d:"vending machine"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:305,question:"The activity which entails buying of goods in bulk and selling in small quantities to retailers is ",option:{a:"assembling ",b:"wholesaling ",c:"retailing ",d:"merchandising "},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:306,question:"The comparison of a country’s visible and invisible exports and imports expressed in monetary term is ",option:{a:"balance of payment ",b:"terms of trade",c:"balance of trade",d:"terms of payment "},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:307,question:"The document that gives an importer a freehand to obtain goods from any manufacturer is ",option:{a:"a consular invoice ",b:"a closed indent ",c:"an open indent ",d:"a freight note"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:308,question:"Entrepot trade usually occurs in ",option:{a:"exchanging goods within a nation ",b:"exchanging goods among countries ",c:"importing goods among countries ",d:"exporting goods to be re-exported "},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:309,question:"The document issued to a port authority when goods are deposited is a ",option:{a:"dock landing account ",b:"bill of sight ",c:"bill of lading ",d:"dock warrant "},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:310,question:"The details of the goods required by the purchaser is outlined in ",option:{a:"a consular invoice ",b:"an indent ",c:"an invoice ",d:"a certificate of origin "},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:311,question:"Selling goods in foreign countries at prices below their marginal cost is ",option:{a:"dumping ",b:"depreciation ",c:"devaluation ",d:"discounting "},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:312,question:"A process of creating more market for a product is through ",option:{a:"consumerism ",b:"marketing ",c:"advertising ",d:"repositioning."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:313,question:"One of the merits of television as a medium of advertising is that it ",option:{a:"is prone to censorship ",b:"is relatively cheap ",c:"has more sensory stimulation ",d:"has more network coverage"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:314,question:"The best mode of ensuring that items posted get to the named addressed is through",option:{a:"recorded delivery ",b:"registered mail",c:"certificate of posting ",d:"express mail"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:315,question:"A businessman who undertakes the hull insurance policy is aiming at ",option:{a:"covering losses on damages to the cargo ",b:"protecting injured crew in the ship ",c:"averting payment of the freight ",d:"covering damages to the body of the ship "},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:316,question:"An agent who brings a customer into business contact with his principal is known as ",option:{a:"a del credere agent ",b:"an auctioneer",c:"a factor",d:"a broker"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:317,question:"A major hindrance to tourism growth in Nigeria is ",option:{a:"absence of genuine tour operators ",b:"lack of tourism master plan ",c:"inadequate tourist centres",d:"non-compliance to immigration laws."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:318,question:"The warehouse that is owned and controlled by the government is a ",option:{a:"wholesalers’ warehouse ",b:"public warehouse ",c:"state warehouse",d:"manufacturers’ warehouse"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:319,question:"One of the main features of a partnership is ",option:{a:"limited liability ",b:"lack of corporate existence ",c:"unlimited membership ",d:"lack of mutual confidence"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:320,question:"An arrangement by independent firms to share the market of their products on quota basis is referred to as  ",option:{a:"trust ",b:"integration ",c:"syndicate ",d:"cartel"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:321,question:"An illegal arrangement by manufacturers to control the price or condition of sale of a product is ",option:{a:"ring ",b:"factoring ",c:"consortium ",d:"merger"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:322,question:"A public company with an authorized capital of N60,000, issued 36,000 shraes at 150k each. What is its capital?",option:{a:"N60,000",b:"N36,000",c:"N54,000",d:"N90,000"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:323,question:"One of the functions of NACCIMA is ",option:{a:"negotiating with labour unions in matters of wages and conditions of service",b:"pooling of members’ resources for long-term investment ",c:"disseminating information to members on matters relating to tariffs ",d:"ensuring uniformity in labour matters and industrial relations."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:324,question:"A characteristic of money which ensures that its value is not lost is ",option:{a:"homogeneity ",b:"easy portability ",c:"divisibility ",d:"relative scarcity "},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:325,question:"The instrument used in the capital market is ",option:{a:"treasury bill ",b:"bill of exchange ",c:"stock ",d:"debenture "},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:326,question:"A pre-requisite for admission into the second-tier securities Market is for a company to ",option:{a:"make 20% of its equity share available to he public for subscription ",b:"have a minimum of 100 shareholders ",c:"have a maximum of 100 shareholders ",d:"make 10% of its equity share available to the public for subscription"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:327,question:"The tree components of staffing are ",option:{a:"recruitment, interview and appointment ",b:"recruitment, test and placement ",c:"recruitment, selection and appointment ",d:"recruitment, selection and placement "},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:328,question:"Which of the following is a matter of personal preference on the part of a superior officer?",option:{a:"Unity of command ",b:"span of control ",c:"delegation of authority ",d:"unity of direction"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:329,question:"The conversion of raw materials into finished goods leads to the creation of ",option:{a:"form utility ",b:"product utility ",c:"possession utility ",d:"place utility "},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:330,question:"The main concern of marketing concept is to ",option:{a:"reduce the number of retail outlets ",b:"identify consumer needs and satisfy them ",c:"increase sales to meet consumer needs ",d:"encourage division of labour."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:331,question:"The best pricing strategy for a company that produces warm clothing is ",option:{a:"target return pricing ",b:"bid pricing ",c:"variable pricing ",d:"product line pricing "},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:332,question:"The deliberate and sustained efforts of an organization towards the creation of goodwill for its products and services is through ",option:{a:"Public relations ",b:"advertising ",c:"sales promotion ",d:"rebranding "},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:333,question:"The label on a product such as ‘pampers’ is a type of ",option:{a:"trademark  ",b:"branding ",c:"packaging ",d:"patent right"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:334,question:"An opportunity to reject a binding contract at will by a third party is said to be a ",option:{a:"valid contract ",b:"quasi contract ",c:"voidable contract",d:"conditional  contract"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:335,question:"An agency contract must involve ",option:{a:"a principal and a consumer",b:"a principal  and a producer ",c:"a principal and a third party ",d:"a principal and a third party "},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:336,question:"The difference between trademark and patent right is that the latter ",option:{a:"gives exclusive right to import a particular good ",b:"is conferred by the government ",c:"confers monopoly  on a product ",d:"confers exclusive right to publish literary works."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:337,question:"Which of the following is a function of consumerism? ",option:{a:"Protecting consumers’ rights ",b:"providing consumers’ choice",c:"providing consumers’ needs",d:"Making profiteering impossible"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:338,question:"A printed copy of processed information from the computer is the ",option:{a:"soft copy ",b:"file copy ",c:"scanned copy ",d:"hard copy "},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:339,question:"The central working system of a computer used for data processing is the ",option:{a:"memory unit ",b:"monitor ",c:"floppy disk drive ",d:"hard drive"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:340,question:"The major problem confronting Cyber Café operators is ",option:{a:"Advanced fee fraud by clientele ",b:"poor network coverage ",c:"high operating costs ",d:"copyright violations by clients"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:341,question:"A device that enables the downloading of information from the internet is the ",option:{a:"floppy drive ",b:"compact disk ",c:"modem ",d:"blue tooth "},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:342,question:"In e-baking, ATM means ",option:{a:"authentic Teller Machine",b:"Automatic Teller Machine ",c:"All-purpose Teller Machine",d:"Automated Teller Machine"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:343,question:"One way by which a business can discharge its social responsibility to its community is to ",option:{a:"hold monthly meetings of its customers",b:"build houses for its executives ",c:"award scholarship to staff children ",d:"build public health centres."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"}],o={subject:e,status:200,total:49,data:i};export{i as data,o as default,t as status,e as subject,a as total};
